Chase Crawford Charlotte, NC 28204 | (980) 308-3055 | chasecrawford2018@gmail.com

June 1, 2020

To whom it may concern:

I am a self-taught software developer who specializes under the .NET Core Framework with approximately four years of practical experience. My recent focus has been integration development utilizing microservices though I do have experience in other areas such as web & desktop applications. My development background has included software refactoring & debugging, API integration, and data pipelines for custom ETL solutions.

Even though I have experience with many different technologies which you will find on my resume the ones I have listed below are those which I either extensively use or I am strongly familiar with.

Key Technologies:

- Languages: C#, PowerShell, JavaScript, jQuery
- Architecture Frameworks: Microservices
- ORM Frameworks: Entity Frameworks
- Frontend Frameworks: Bootstrap
- Design Patterns: MVC, MVVM
- Reporting: Power BI, SSRS
- Database Management: Microsoft SQL Server
- Networking: Microsoft Azure, Microsoft Active Directory, IIS

I have an extraordinarily strong passion for programming and would love the opportunity to work with an experienced team to further my knowledge and experience within my career. If applicable for the position please feel free to contact me at (980) 308-3055 or chasecrawford2018@gmail.com. Thank you for your time.

Sincerely,

Chase Crawford

Enclosure: Résumé

1010 Kenilworth Ave Apt 126 Charlotte NC, 28204

(980)-308-3055 chasecrawford2018@gmail.com

Education:

Sep 2014 – Jun 2019

East Carolina University, College of Business, Greenville, NC.

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration; Operations & Supply Chain Management

Work Experience:

Nov 2019 – Apr 2020

DCLI (Direct Chassislink Inc), Charlotte NC

BI Software Developer

- Developed and implemented API integration solutions for extracting and loading data across various warehouses.
- Developed light weight UI's for managing and centralizing external services.
- Managed a pre-existing API Gateway.

Jun 2019 - Nov 2019

Lowe's Corporate, Mooresville NC

BI Software Developer, Contractor

- Migrated entire instance of 08 on SQL Server to 2016 version.
- Converted and refactored SSRS Reports into Power BI Reports.
- Maintained and enhanced client-side applications which were written in VB or C#.

Sep 2017 – Jun 2019

Denso Manufacturing North Carolina (formally ASMO Greenville of North Carolina Inc.), Greenville NC

Production Control Specialist

Technical Expertise:

Environments: Windows, Linux Cloud Services: Microsoft Azure

Frameworks: ASP.NET, .Net Core, Bootstrap

Architectures & Design Patterns: N'Tier, Microservices, Integration, MVC, MVVM, Singleton

Reporting, ETL, Analysis: Microsoft SSDT, Power BI, Tableau

Programming Languages: C#, Python, VB

Other Languages: JavaScript, PowerShell, ASP, VBScript, M Language, DAX

Database Management: Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL Server, Teradata, IBM DB2

Other: TQM, Lean Manufacturing, Six Sigma, MRP (Material Requirement Planning), APP (Aggregated

Production Planning), ECI Planning (Engineering Change Instruction), SAP, AS/400, Oracle

Miscellaneous:

GitHub: https://github.com/chasec2018 Webpage: https://chasercrawford.com

Professional Projects:

Previous projects have been managed in both Agile & Traditional structures

- Backflush Implementation Projects (Denso Corporation)
- Internal Dashboarding Project (Denso Corporation)
- Microsoft SQL Server Migration Project (Lowe's Corporation)
- SSRS Conversion to Power BI & On-Premise Data Gateway Standup (Lowe's Corporation)
- Vendor Management System Enhancement Project (Lowe's Corporation)
- Tableau Server API Integration Project (DCLI)
- GIER Registry Integration Project (DCLI)